# **Elliot Himmelfarb**

A quick learning, full-stack JavaScript developer out to change the world.

developer.passions = [
 building, creating, learning, growing, self-improving, programming,
];

2915 Baseline Rd, Unit 514 Boulder, CO 80308

(626) 639-5973

ellioth@futurecode.ninja

http://futurecode.ninja/

https://github.com/elliothimmelfarb

https://www.linkedin.com/in/elliot-himmelfarb-1434797

### **PROJECTS**

# **Arduino Mood Chat App** — *Angular, Node, Express, Socket.io, IBM Watson Tone Analyzer, Arduino*

https://github.com/eileenzhong/third-hackathon

Hackathon Project - Sends messages through IBM Watson's Tone Analyzer and colors an Arduino LED accordingly.

# **Yelp off Yelp** — MEAN stack, Yelp API, Satellizer.js, BCryptJS, JWT, Pug, Sass, Gulp

https://github.com/elliothimmelfarb/yelp-business-search-tracker

Search Yelp.com. Save and remove favorites. See how many times a business has been favorited by others.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# **Coding House** — *Code Mentor*

Pleasanton, CA | July 2016 - PRESENT

- Reviewing code and assisting students
- Building production grade apps individually and in teams
- Studying CS concepts while learning new frameworks and skills

# Ewha Little Campus, Ulsan

# MapleBear Canadian Immersion School, Seoul

### — Foreign English Teacher

South Korea | March 2014 - March 2016

- Created lesson plans and classroom materials;
- 8 classes per day, 5 days per week;
- Cultural interface for parents, students, school administration.

### **EDUCATION**

## **Coding House** — Full-Stack Javascript Development

Fremont, CA | June 2016 - August 2016

# **University of Oregon** — B.A Cultural and Archaeological Anthropology

Eugene, OR | August 2009 - July 2013

#### **Proficient**

FS6

Angular 1.5

React

ISX

Redux

Node

**Express** 

MongoDB

Mongoose

**MEAN Stack** 

HTML5

CSS3

Sass

Bootstrap

Pug/Jade

jQuery

Gulp

Google Maps API's

Websockets

REST

APIs

Airbnb's ES6/REACT/JSX Style Guides

John Papa's Angular 1 Style Guide

### **Exposure**

Flux

Mocha

AWS S3

Firebase

Chai

**IBM Watson** 

Webpack

Java

Python

C++

MySQL

TDD